Inventory of the Thomas Byrne Edsall papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Thomas Byrne Edsall papers
1965-2014
88024
Hoover Institution Archives
259 manuscript boxes, 8 oversize boxes (113.0 linear feet)
Writings, correspondence, notes, memoranda, poll data, statistics, printed matter, and photographs relating to American politics during the presidential administration of Ronald Reagan, especially with regard to campaign contributions and effects on income distribution; and to the gubernatorial administration of Michael Dukakis in Massachusetts, especially with regard to state economic policy, and the campaign of Michael Dukakis as the Democratic candidate for president of the United States in 1988; and to social conditions in the United States.
Edsall, Thomas Byrne.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1988, with increments received in subsequent years.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1941 August 22 Born, Cambridge, Massachusetts
1959-1961 Attended Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island
1965 Reporter, Providence Journal, Rhode Island
1966 B.A., Boston University, Massachusetts
1966-1967 Volunteer worker, Volunteers in Service to America (VISTA), Maryland
1967-1981 Reporter, Baltimore Sun, Maryland
1981 Recipient, Bill Pryor Memorial Award and Front Page Award from Washington Baltimore Newspaper Guild
1981-2006 Reporter, Washington Post
1984 Author, The New Politics of Inequality
1989 Contributor, The Rise and Fall of the New Deal Order
1991 Author, Chain Reaction: The Impact of Race, Rights, and Taxes on American Politics
1996-1997 Fellowship, Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars
2006-2013 Correspondent, The New Republic
2006-2014 Joseph Pulitzer II and Edith Pulitzer Moore Professor of Public Affairs Journalism, Columbia University
2007-2009 Political editor, Huffington Post
2011- Columnist, New York Times online
Scope and Content of Collection
The Thomas Byrne Edsall papers relate to American politics during the presidential administration of Ronald Reagan, especially with regard to campaign contributions and effects on income distribution; and to the gubernatorial administration of Michael Dukakis in Massachusetts, especially with regard to state economic policy, and the campaign of Michael Dukakis as the Democratic candidate for president of the United States in 1988; and to social conditions in the United States. They consist of correspondence, memoranda, notes, poll data, printed matter, statistics, writings, and photographs.
An increment received in 2005 (boxes 130-253) consists chiefly of research materials and draft manuscripts for an unpublished book on American men.
Dukakis, Michael S. (Michael Stanley),1933-; Democratic Party (U.S.); Massachusetts--Politics and government--1951-; Massachusetts--Economic conditions.; Presidents--United States--Election--1988.; United States--Politics and government--1981-1989.; Journalists.; Reagan, Ronald.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); United States--Economic policy--1981-1993.; United States--Social conditions--1980-
- Key election--Votes for governor of Massachusetts by county, undated (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Printed matter
- Interview of Ed King, former governor of Massachusetts, and Chet Atkins, Massachusetts State Democratic Chairman, by John McLaughlin, 1988 May 1 (Box 1)
  Typescript
- Press release, report, and speeches relating to various issues from the office of Michael Dukakis, governor of Massachusetts, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
- Health care, 1988 (Box 1)
- Budget (Massachusetts), 1984-1988 (Box 1)
  Includes related financial data from Massachusetts Technology Development Corporation (MTDC), Thrift Fund, and Massachusetts Industrial Finance Agency (MIFA), etc.
- Articles by Thomas Edsall, 1988 (Box 1)
  Typescripts
- Clippings, 1988 (Box 1)
- Miscellany, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
- Dukakis for President Committee Information Report, undated (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Printed articles, 1984-1987 (Box 2)
- Budget (Massachusetts), fiscal year, 1989 (Box 2)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1985-1988 (Box 2)
- Articles by Thomas Edsall, Dukakis I, II, III, and final, Washington Post, 1988 (Box 2)
- Massachusetts Industrial Finance Agency (MIFA), 1987 (Box 2)
  Brochure
- Annual report, Massachusetts Community Development Finance Corporation (CDFC), 1987, and Investment Programs, undated (Box 2)
- Records of Thrift Fund, 1988 (Box 2)
- Annual report, Massachusetts Capital Resource Company (MCRC), 1987 (Box 2)
- Massachusetts Government Land Bank, undated (Box 2)
  Includes annual report, 1987-1988
- Printed articles, 1988 (Box 2)
- Curriculum vitae of others, undated (Box 2)
- Massachusetts Industrial Finance Agency (MIFA), 1987 (Box 2)
- Massachusetts Technology Development Corporation (MTDC), 1987 (Box 2)
- Financial statements, Massachusetts Technology Park Corporation, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
- Miscellany, 1982-1988 (Box 2)
- "Dukakis 1988," early drafts (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
- Time, 1988
- Massachusetts Industrial Finance Agency (MIFA), 1987 (Box 3)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1988 (Box 3)
- "Creating the Future: Economic Innovation for the Twentieth Century," report of the Governor's Advisory Committee on Innovation, Commonwealth of Massachusetts, 1986 October (Box 3)
- "Expanding Opportunity," the Governor's budget recommendations for the fiscal year 1989, Commonwealth of Massachusetts, 1988 January 27 (Box 3)
- Massachusetts election statistics, 1986 (Box 3)
- Miscellany, undated (Box 3)
- New York 1988 (active and inactive) (Box-folder 4: 1-2)
  Includes clippings, data sheets, and other related materials
- Clippings and printed matter, 1984-1988 (Box 4)
- Annual report, Bay State Skills Corporation, 1987 (Box 4)
- "Expanding Opportunity," the governor's budget recommendations for the fiscal year 1989, Commonwealth of Massachusetts, 1988 January 27 (Box 4)
- The Economist, 1988 (Box 4)
- Massachusetts Center of Excellence: A State Opportunity, undated (Box 4)
- "Economic Performance and Economic Development Policy in Massachusetts," Ronald F. Ferguson and Helen F. Ladd, discussion paper, John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1986 (Box 4)
- "Economic Profile of Gwinnett County," report, 1987 December (Box 4)
- Compact sound cassettes (Box 4)
  - Undated and unidentified (Box 4)
  - "Vital Message from Pat Robertson," (side A) and "An Evaluation of 1988," (side B) (Box 4)
- Miscellany, undated (Box 4)
- Thomas Edsall, week of, 1988 January 17 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  Miscellaneous materials
- GOP--Texas, 1988 (Box-folder 5: 2)
- Interviews--Texas, 1985 (Box-folder 5: 3)
- Clippings, 1988 (Box-folder 5: 4)
- Notebooks (8), 1988 (Box 5)
- 8 mini sound cassettes, 1988 May (Box 5)
- Miscellany, 1988 (Box 5)
  Includes clippings and data sheets
- Wattenbert, 1988 (Box-folder 6: 1)
- Miscellaneous materials
  - Georgia, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Tennessee, 1987 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - North Carolina, 1987 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Kentucky, 1987 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Texas, 1987 (Box-folder 6: 6-7)
  - South--Simon, undated (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - South--GOP, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 6: 9-10)
  - Florida, 1987 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Blacks--South, 1987 (Box-folder 6: 12)
- Super Tuesday--Facts, 1988 (Box-folder 6: 13)
- Election Politics, A Journal of Political Campaigns and Elections, 1987-1988 Winter (Box 6)
- Tabulation of official votes: Florida--General election, 1980 November 4, 1986 (Box 6)
- "Factions in the Texas Republican Party," David B. Hill, Annual Meeting of the American Political Science Association, Palmer House, Massachusetts?, 1987 September 3-6 (Box 6)
- "Measures of Real Earnings Since 1970," Congressional Research Service (CRS) report for Congress, 1987 (Box 6)
- Stanley B. Greenberg (Box 6)
  - Report on Democratic defection, 1985 April 15 (Box 6)
  - "Making the Tough Issues Work,", 1986 September 25 (Box 6)
- "The Youth Problem: Age or Generational Crowding?" David E. Bloom and Richard B. Freeman, 1986 April (Box 6)
- Republican--Directory, 1987 (Box 6)
- Notebook, undated (Box 6)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1972-1988 (Box 6)
  Includes data sheets
- "Text Two," unidentified and undated compact sound cassette (Box 6)
- Clippings, 1986-1988 (Box 7)
- ADA voting records, 1967-1973 (Box 7)
- "Ronald Reagan and the Reconstruction of American Politics: Creating a Supply Side Society," Benjamin Ginsberg and Martin Shefter, 1986 Annual Meeting of the American Political Science Association, Washington, D.C., 1986 August 28-31 (Box 7)
- "What Is Happening to the Middle Class?" McKinley L. Blackburn and David E. Bloom, 1985 January (Box 7)
  Photocopy
- "The Changing Shape of the Massachusetts Political Universe," Walter Dean Burnham, 1984 (Box 7)
- Polling data, 1986 (Box 7)
- Tax information, 1988 (Box 7)
- Miscellany (Box 7)
  Includes program of the American Economic Association, photocopies of articles, brochures, and press releases from the Federal Election Commission, 1986
- New York Review of Books--Post-1988 election (Box-folder 8: 1)
- Tikkun, 1986 December (Box-folder 8: 2)
  Articles, letters, and printed matter
- Democratic National Party (DNC), 1986 (Box-folder 8: 3)
- New Populist Forum, panel discussion, undated (Box-folder 8: 4)
- Senate, 1986 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  Clippings
- Negative campaign, 1986 (Box-folder 8: 6)
- Reports of receipts and disbursements and campaign summary report, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 8: 7)
- Robert Teeter and Robert Silvers, 1986 February (Box-folder 8: 8)
  Includes articles, graphs, memorandum, printed matter, and report
- Dissent
  - 1986 August (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - 1987 February (Box-folder 8: 10)
- Money, 1986 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  Typescript article
- Dukakis materials to be added to Duke series, 1988 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  Typescript, clippings, and printed matter
- Honoraria, 1987 June 6 (Box-folder 8: 13)
- South--, 1987 May 16 (Box-folder 8: 14)
- Michigan Op-Ed, 1987 May 27 (Box-folder 8: 15)
- Articles by Thomas Edsall about Carl R. (Spitz) Channell, 1986 December (Box-folder 8: 16)
- Post-election outlook, 1986 November (Box-folder 8: 17)
  Articles by Thomas Edsall. Typescript
- Terry Dolan, 1986 November (Box-folder 8: 18)
  Court records
- Review of Politics and Society in the South, Earl Black and Merle Black, 1987 April 17 (Box-folder 8: 19)
- "Equality," The New Republic, 1985 (Box-folder 8: 20)
- Best clips, Washington Post, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 8: 21)
- Vote brochure, 1988 (Box 8)
- Articles by Robert L. Woodson, 1980-1985 (Box 8)
  Includes related brochures, clippings, and printed matter
- Correspondence with Ann Hukbert, New Republic (Box 8)
  Includes articles by Thomas Edsall, 1985-1986
- Op-ed, 1985 March (Box-folder 9: 1)
- Brake, 1985 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  Original of "Outlook" piece
- Slide talk, Harvard University, 1985 (Box-folder 9: 3)
- Washington Monthly, 1985 (Box-folder 9: 4)
- Poll--John Martin's memorandum, 1978 February (Box-folder 9: 5)
- Magazine drafts, undated (Box-folder 9: 6)
  Typescript and printed copy
- Weapons, 1980 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  Clippings and related materials
- Indiana, undated (Box-folder 9: 8)
  Notes
- "Corporate PACs" (Political Action Committees), Management, Graduate School of Management Magazine, University of California, Los Angeles, 1984 (Box-folder 9: 9)
- Schmick III, William F.--Resume, undated (Box-folder 9: 10)
- GOP (op-ed), 1985 (Box-folder 9: 11)
- Marcos, Ferdinand, 1986 (Box-folder 9: 12)
- New Republic--Piece and outline, 1985 January (Box-folder 9: 13)
- Dissent, 1985 January (Box-folder 9: 14)
- Articles by Thomas Edsall, undated (Box 9)
- Republican governors' conference, 1988 (Box 9)
  Printed conference directory
- Miscellany--Brochures, map, polling data, and other printed materials, 1988 (Box 9)
- Pantheon books (Box 10)
  - Correspondence relating to the publication of the work provisionally titled, "Untitled Collection of Essays on the Reagan Years" (Box-folder 10: 1-2)
    Includes typescript notes and clippings, 1986-1988
  - "The Reagan Legacy"
    - Hype, undated (Box-folder 10: 3-4)
    - Copy edit, 1988 (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - Legacy--Introduction, 1988 (Box-folder 10: 6-7)
    - Typescript chapters, undated (Box 10)
    - Jacket, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Biographies of contributors, 1987 (Box 10)
    - Typescript notes, 1988 (Box 10)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1987-1988 (Box 10)
- Data sheet, 1988 (Box 10)
- "The Reagan Legacy" (Box 11)
  - Revised versions by David Ignatius, 1987 (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
  - Old versions, 1987 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - 2nd version requested by Sidney Blumenthal, 1987 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Typescript chapters by Robert Kuttner, 1987 (Box-folder 11: 5-6)
  - Revised version by Lincoln Caplan, 1987 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - Draft typescript chapters by Thomas Edsall, 1987 (Box-folder 11: 8)
  - Notes, 1987 (Box-folder 11: 9)
- Correspondence with Jim Peck, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 11: 10)
- John B. Judis
  - "Conservatism and the Price of Success,", 1987 (Box-folder 11: 11)
    Typescript. Includes correspondence, 1988
  - "Post-Reagan Conservatism,", undated (Box-folder 11: 12)
- Miscellany, 1987 (Box 11)
- The Robbins Office, Inc., 1988 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  Correspondence
- "The Reagan Legacy"--Copyright, 1988 (Box-folder 12: 2)
- "The Political Legacy of the Reagan Years," William Schneider, contributor, 1987 (Box-folder 12: 3)
- "The Reagan Legacy," Thomas B. Edsall, undated (Box 12)
  Typescript chapters
- Parts of chapters from "The Reagan Legacy" by different contributors--Sidney Blumenthal, Thomas Edsall, David Ignatius, John B. Judis, Lincoln Kaplan, Robert Kuttner, and William Schneider. (Box 12)
- "Reagan Legacy"--Index, undated (Box 12)
- Proofs of articles to be published in The Atlantic, 1988 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  Typescript and printed copies
- Correspondence with the Atlantic, 1988 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  Includes printed articles
- Day list file--Daily schedule and agenda, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 13: 3)
- Clippings, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 13: 4)
- Photocopies of financial records, 1975-1983 (Box 13)
- Miscellany--Printed matter, 1982-1987 (Box 13)
  Includes brochure, holograph notes, and press release
- Speech for Robert Kuttner's class, Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University, 1986 January (Box-folder 14: 1)
- Speech, National Colloquium, Ohio Wesleyan University, Delaware, Ohio, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  Typescript draft. Includes related materials
- Speech, Northwestern University, Chicago, 1988 May 21 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  Typescript draft
- Article, New York Review of Books, 1987 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  Typescript. Includes copies of New York Review of Books, 1986-1987
- Steve Symms for Senate Committee (April 15th report), 1980 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  Includes correspondence and financial records
- "Effective Corporate Tax Rates and Tax Changes in the 97th Congress," Jane G. Gravelle, 1983 January 3 (Box 14)
- "Business War on the Law: An Analysis of the Benefits of Federal Health/Safety Enforcement," Mark Green and Norman Waitzman, 1981 (Box 14)
- Center for the Study of American Business, Annual Review, 1982 (Box 14)
  Printed copy
- "Health Care and the States," conference proceedings, sponsored by the American Legislative Exchange Council, Washington, D.C., 1982 May 14-15 (Box 14)
- "Senate Issues: Yearbook 1985." (Box 14)
- "Toward a More Open Trade Policy," Murray L. Weidenbaum (co-authored with Michael C. Munger and Ronald J. Penoyer), Center for the Study of American Business, 1983 January (Box 14)
- Hoover Institution report, 1982 (Box 14)
- "Business PACs and Ideology: A Study of Contributions in the 1982 Elections," Stuart Rothenberg and Richard R. Roldan, 1983 (Box 14)
- Photocopies of articles by Martin Feldstein, undated (Box 14)
- The National Congressional Club--Brochure, undated (Box 14)
- Miscellany, 1977-1986 (Box 14)
  Chart, notes, and printed matter
- Business Industry Political Action Committee (BIPAC), 1981-1982 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  Includes background materials, brochures, directory, fliers, list of contributions, report covering political developments of 1982 January, statement, and testimony
- The Political Report, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 15: 2)
- Federal Election Commission--Receipts and disbursements, undated; Tax Notes, 1982 July 12; and candidate index of supporting documents, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 15: 3)
- Remarks, Paul Thayer, on the occasion of the acceptance of the position of Chairman of the Board, Chamber of Commerce of the United States, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  Typescript. Includes articles by others, letters, and reports
- Articles by Thomas Edsall, 1982 (Box-folder 15: 5)
- Notes, Thomas Edsall, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  Typescript and holograph. Includes printed matter
- List of AGC Political Action Committee (PAC) contributions to candidates, 1981 January - December (Box-folder 15: 7)
  Includes related materials
- Federal Election Commission (FEC), 1977-1982 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  Includes press releases and Political Action Committee (PAC) contributions
- Notes on money, 1982 (Box-folder 15: 9)
  Includes "We Will Help Our Friends First," Edward J. Rollins, National Journal, 1982 June 12, and "The GOP Wants You," National Journal, 1981 October 3
- "Political Action Committees: The Highest Bidders," CBS Evening News with Dan Rather, CBS Television Network, 1982 February 22-26 (Box-folder 15: 10)
  Typescript transcript
- Report of receipts and disbursements for an authorized committee, and itemized receipts, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 15: 11-12)
- Political Wildcatter, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 15: 13)
- Photocopies of articles by Robert Engler, New Republic, 1955 August 29 and September 26 (Box 15)
- The Washington Post, National Weekly Edition, 1982 October 25 (Box 15)
- "The Rise and Fall of New Deal Liberalism," to be published by Princeton University Press, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  Includes correspondence, notes, drafts, and a typescript article, "The Changing Shape of Power: A Realignment in Public Policy," 1988 January 1
- Dissent, 1986 (Box-folder 16: 2)
  Includes "And Now, the Political Consequences?" undated, and "Letter from Washington," by Thomas Edsall, 1986 October. Typescript
- Kirk O'Donnell--Introduction. (Box-folder 16: 3)
  Includes "Where's the Party? An Assessment of Changes in Party Loyalty and Party Coalitions in the 1980s," introduction by Thomas Edsall, Center for National Policy, 1987 March, and articles by others
- Power and Money: Writing About Politics, 1971-1987, Thomas Edsall, 1988 (Box 16)
- The New Politics of Inequality, 1984, Thomas Edsall, and The Reagan Legacy, edited by Sidney Blumenthal and Thomas Edsall, 1988 (Box 16)
- Printed matter, 1980-1988 (Box 16)
- "Epilogue," rough and final drafts, notes, and letter from W. W. Norton & Company, 1987 (Box-folder 17: 1)
- Acknowledgements, 1987 (Box-folder 17: 2)
- Biography, Thomas Edsall, undated (Box-folder 17: 3)
- "Power and Money: Writings on Politics 1971-1987," book title and an introduction, undated (Box-folder 17: 4)
- List of things to do for the clips book, 1987 August 31 (Box-folder 17: 5)
- Power and Money, 1988 (Box-folder 17: 6)
  Typescript. Includes introduction and an article titled, "Epilogue"
- Power and Money, 1971-1987
  - Chapter I. (Box-folder 17: 7)
    Typescript. Includes printed matter, 1971-1977, and typescript writings about Marvin Mandel, undated
  - Chapter II and printed matter, 1977-1985 (Box-folder 17: 8)
  - Chapter III, "Early Reagan Years,", 1981-1987 (Box-folder 17: 9)
  - Chapter IV, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 17: 10)
  - Chapter V, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 17: 11)
  - Bibliography, 1966-1987 (Box-folder 17: 12)
- Federal Election Commission (FEC), 1987 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  Typescript chapter
- Extra study lists for clips book, 1987; marked story lists to go out with permission forms and short explanatory letter, 1987; photocopies of permission slips, 1987; permission forms, letter, and addresses of magazines, 1987; and an article by Thomas Edsall, Washington Post, 1987 October 30 (Box-folder 18: 2)
- Clips hype, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  Printed copies of articles by others. Includes Proceedings of the Institute of Politics, John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University, 1986-1987
- "Outlook"
  - Ideas, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - Realignment, 1986 September (Box-folder 18: 5)
- "Power and Money: Writing about Politics,", 1980-1983 (Box 18)
  Includes typescript notes and rough drafts
- Comments about Thomas Edsall and others, Media Guide, undated (Box 18)
- Printed copies of articles by others, 1984-1986 (Box 18)
- Remarks, Dan Quayle, Enlisted Association, National Guard of the United States, 1988 August 24 (Box 18)
  Typescript excerpts
- Message from Mike Dukakis, undated (Box 18)
- Traveling press schedule, undated (Box 18)
- Dukakis/Bentsen campaign 1988 press advisory and manifesto, 1988 October 21 (Box 18)
- Thomas Edsall: Defense Contractual Series, 1971-1990 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  Includes originals and copies of articles
- Correspondence with The Atlantic, 1987-1988; "The Changing of Power: A Realignment in Public Policy," 1987 December 1; and "The Return of Inequality," (Box-folder 19: 2)
- Frenkil, notes relating to the case of defrauding the government, undated (Box-folder 19: 3)
- Review of David Vogel, Fluctuating Fortunes: The Political Power of Business in America, by Bruce Jackson, Basic Books, 1989 May - June 5 (Box-folder 19: 4-5)
  Typescript and printed copy. Includes revised version, New York Review of Books, and related materials
- Marvin Mandel file, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 19: 6)
  Includes clippings and copies of articles
- "GOP's Gains in South Pose Dilemma,", 1988 December 5 (Box-folder 19: 7)
- "Reality of Governing," rough drafts?, undated (Box-folder 19: 8)
- 1 photographic print depicting an unidentified individual, undated (Box 19)
- Campaign 1980--Letter from Philip M. Crane to Thomas Edsall, 1978 September 12 (Box-folder 20: 1)
- Mailing and clip lists, and Business Lobby Series lists, 1980 (Box-folder 20: 2)
- The Washington Journalism Center and Harvard University fellowships, typescript drafts of statements to be included in the application, and a letter of reference from Karl W. Deutsch, 1973 March (Box-folder 20: 3)
- Information regarding American Political Science Association Congressional Fellowships, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 20: 4)
- Riot Game--Charts, clipping, and notes, undated (Box-folder 20: 5)
- "And the Walls Came Tumbling Down," Randel Barnett, Baltimore Magazine, 1980 May (Box-folder 20: 6)
- Major points to be made in memorandum to The Sun, undated (Box-folder 20: 7)
- Conflict of interest legislation and "Ethics,", 1973 (Box-folder 20: 8)
  Typescript article and memorandum
- "Reality of Governing," original typescript drafts, undated (Box-folder 20: 9)
  Includes handwritten notes and "Congress Turns Rightward," Thomas Edsall, Dissent, 1978 winter
- "Lobbying Law Reform in Maryland: A Prerequisite to Increased Citizen Confidence in Government," Bruce Adams, 1975 (Box-folder 20: 10)
- Francis Scott Bank and Trust Company hearing, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 20: 11)